Guide to the George Platt Lynes Diaries and Memorabilia
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
George Platt Lynes diaries and memorabilia
1921-1955
YCAL MSS 147
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.06
(3 boxes)
The George Platt Lynes diaries consist of diaries and datebooks which record his activities and thoughts, starting with a journal of Lynes' first trip to Europe in 1925 and ending with entries in a pocket datebook just weeks before his death in 1955. Though his early and later years are well documented, there are no diaries for the years 1931-1941. Accompanying the diaries are a few odd pieces of personal memorabilia, including a notebook of dinners given during the early 1940s and printed versions of writings by Glenway Wescott form the early 1920s.
Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received with the Glenway Wescott papers, purchase from Monroe Wheeler, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Additional George Platt Lynes material can be found in the Glenway Wescott Papers [YCAL MSS 134] and the Monroe Wheeler Papers [YCAL MSS 136]. The materials included in this collection represent items that were already segregated when received with the original papers.
GEORGE PLATT LYNES [1907-1955]
George Platt Lynes is best known as a portrait, fashion, and nude photographer. He spent several years living with and traveling with Glenway Wescott and Monroe Wheeler.
Scope and Contents
The George Platt Lynes Diaries & Memorabilia is organized into two series. Series I, Diaries, the largest component, consists of diaries and datebooks which record his activities and thoughts, starting with a journal of Lynes' first trip to Europe in 1925 and ending with entries in a pocket datebook just weeks before his death in 1955. Though his early and later years are well documented, there are no diaries for the years 1931-1941. Series II, Memorabilia, consists of a few odd personal items, including a notebook of dinners given during the early 1940s and printed versions of writings by Glenway Wescott.
Photographers -- United States; Diaries; Photographers; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-1987; Wheeler, Monroe, 1899-1988
- Diaries, 1925-1955; Series I; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  - "My Trip Abroad" diary, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Five-year diary, 1925-26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Year-by-Year" Book, 1928-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diary, [1942] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Datebook, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Datebook, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Datebooks, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Datebook, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Datebook, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Datebook, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Datebook, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Datebook, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Datebook, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Datebook, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Datebook, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Memorabilia, 1921-1944; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Drawing of GPL by Jean Cocteau [photocopy], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Notebook of dinners and menus, 1943-44 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes guest lists and draft of letter [by Monroe Wheeler?]
  - Printed versions of writings by Glenway Wescott, collected by GPL, 1921-28 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Receipt for tires and product information flyer, 1939, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)